Inventory of the J. H. Rowe Papers, 1913-1937
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
J.H. Rowe papers
1913-1937
Rowe, J.H. (James H.), d. 1945
01013
.45 cubic ft. (1 box)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Correspondence and financial records of oil companies in Montana in the early twentieth century.
Biography of J. H. Rowe
James H. Rowe (d. 1945) was a Montana businessman who engaged in oil exploration and development in the early twentieth century. He was a partner in the Lawlor & Rowe corporation of Butte, Montana.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, reports, maps, and business records of the Seventynine Oil Company and the West Dome Oil Company. Both companies were engaged in developing oil properties under the management of J.H. Rowe.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by J. H. Rowe at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from J.E. Driscoll of Lawlor & Rowe in 1961.
Access Terms
Oil fields -- Montana; Petroleum -- Prospecting -- Montana; Butte (Mont.)
Agriculture and Natural Resources; Mines and Mineral Resources; Energy Production; Montana
Container List
- Ingomar Dome (Montana) - report, 1920 (Box 1)
- Lovell (Wyoming) Refinery - report, 1921 (Box 1)
- Seventynine Oil Company - correspondence, 1913-1916 (Box 1)
- Seventynine Oil Company - stock, 1914-1918 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - cost sheets and business statement, 1921 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - financial statement, 1921 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - lawsuit by Petroleum County (Montana), 1937 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - leases - Fergus County (Montana), 1920 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - map of West Dome, Mosby Structure, undated (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - stock, assets, and other financial papers, 1920-1927 (Box 1)
- West Dome Oil Company - trial balance sheets, 1921, 1925 (Box 1)